Kaito and his friends will return to Japan the day after tomorrow.
（解道バロン）カイト君たちは　あさって
日本に戻ってくるそうです。
（軸川ソウジ）そうですか。
That's good news.
Also, I got word from Chief Rook.
それから　ルーク管理官から
連絡がありました。→
They managed to figure out what Jin was doing during his missing year.
空白の１年間における
ジンの行動は解明できたと。
Enigma's the bigger problem at this point.
エニグマの方は　手ごわいですね。
ＰＯＧの情報網も　いまだ
何も　つかめていません。
The POG's intelligence networks couldn't find anything on him so far.
僕と　キュービック君も
動いているのですが　なかなか…。
Cubik and I are making moves too, but to no avail.
[無線]
ん？
Hello?
分かりました。
では　伺いましょう。
I see. I will be there right away.
学園長…。
Principal?
I think we will get a chance to ask him in person.
疑問は　直接
本人に尋ねる事になりそうです。
Huh?
Let us enjoy puzzles together,
（エニグマ）
さあ　２人で　パズルを楽しもう…。
ラブーシュカ。
Lovushka.
I must admit, your sudden invitation caught me by surprise.
突然のお招き　正直　驚きました。
すまないねえ。
こう見えても　忙しいのだよ。
Pardon me. I'm quite a busy man, despite how it may appear.
スケジュールの合間を縫うのは
何かと大変でね。
Finding a gap in my schedule isn't a simple puzzle.
お久しぶりです　真方ジン。
It's been too long, Makata Jin.
（真方ジン）あなたも
僕の知り合いなのですか？
You're one of my acquaintances as well?
（レイツェル）
いきなり　どういうつもり!?
What's the meaning of this?
（エニグマ）いやぁ…　実は　誰かが
私の身辺を探っているようでね。
Well, it seems that someone's snooping on me.
隠し事はしない。
I have nothing to hide.
Please, if you have any questions, I'd be glad to answer them.
知りたい事があるなら
何でも　お答えしよう。
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）確かに
その方が　話が早いですね。
That way is certainly faster.
質問に入る前に　一つ。
Let me make one thing clear before asking any questions.
僕たちは　ジンが　パズルを
憎んでいたとは考えていません。
We do not believe that Jin hated puzzles.
Oh?
We think that even if he made such statements,
もし　過去に　そのような発言を
していたとしても→
それは
オルペウスの腕輪に　のみこまれ→
that must have been due to the mental distortion of the Orpheus Armlet.
思考が　ゆがめられていたせいだと
考えています。
That is a reasonable and fascinating conclusion.
一理ある。　興味深い推論だね。
フッ。　だが…
本当に　そうだろうか？
But is it correct, I wonder?
（ビショップ）というと？
What do you mean?
私も　腕輪の研究は
進めていてね。
I've made some progress with researching the Armlet.
まあ　君たちほどでは
ないかもしれないが…。→
Though my knowledge might not be as direct as yours,
judging from past cases, I believe that the Armlet amplifies and distorts feelings already in the user's mind.
過去の事例から　腕輪は→
その人間が　もともと持っている
感情や思考を増幅させ→
ゆがめていると　私は考えている。
その点　腕輪をはめていた本人の
意見をお聞きしたいところだが…。
I would certainly appreciate any comments regarding the matter directly from someone who has experienced it.
一理ありますね。
That is plausible.
では　真方ジンの中にも
程度は　どうであれ→
Then the hatred for puzzles, the extent of it aside, existed inside Makata Jin.
パズルに対する憎しみはあった…
という事には　ならないかなあ？
Or is that too far fetched of a conclusion?
可能性は　あります。
It is possible.
ま…　彼の
古い友人である私にとっては→
Though for me, his old friend, that is but an obvious fact.
今更な話だが。
古い…　友人？
Old friend?
私の知っているジンは　いつも
パズルに傷つき　苦しんでいた。
The Jin I knew was tortured and suffered because of puzzles.
レイツェル君。　君は　いつ　どこで
ジンと出会ったのですか？
Raetsel, when and where did you meet him?
I heard that it was in a small mountain village, when he was on his Fools' Puzzle journey.
（エニグマ）
愚者のパズルを巡る旅の途中…→
ある山あいの
小さな村だったそうだ。
あっ!?。→
美しい　パズルだ…。
Such a beautiful puzzle.
（エニグマ）それが　レイツェルだった。→
That was Raetsel.
彼女は　両親を事故で失い→
She'd lost her parents in an accident
近所の人々に助けられ
１人で生活していたそうだ。
and lived alone with the support of her neighbors.
Her parents gave her puzzles for as long as she could remember.
（エニグマ）両親は　幼い頃から　彼女に
パズルを与えていたようだった。
回想
こ…　これも見てみる？
Look at this!
回想
君が作ったのかい？
Did you make it?
Her puzzle skills were off the charts.
（エニグマ）彼女のパズル能力は
すばらしいものだった。→
ＰＯＧが　ピタゴラス伯爵が　その存在に
気付くのも　時間の問題だ。→
It was only a matter of time before the POG and Count Pythagoras would notice her too.
そこで　ジンは　レイツェルを守るため
旅に同行させる事にした。
So to protect her, Jin took Raetsel along on his journey.
She was completely alone, so she trusted and happily joined him.
身寄りのなかった彼女は
ジンに心を許し→
喜んで　ついていったそうだよ。
That's right, Jin.
心の声
（レイツェル）そう…　ジン　あなたは…。
You...
You tried to keep your terrible struggle with Fools' Puzzles a secret from me.
心の声
（レイツェル）愚者のパズルとの
過酷な戦いを→
私には見せまいとしていた。
心の声
（レイツェル）でも…。
But...
回想
（ジン）うっ…　うわっ！
レイツェル！
Raetsel!
Sorry for scaring you.
ごめん…。　怖い思い
させちゃったな。
心の声
（レイツェル）違う。
怖くて泣いたんじゃない。→
No. I didn't cry because I was scared.
I cried because I pitied you.
ジンが　かわいそうだったから。→
You were hurting all alone. I wanted to help you.
１人で傷つくジンを
助けたかったから…。
I couldn't ignore that puzzles were hurting you.
心の声
（レイツェル）私は　あなたを苦しめる
パズルが許せなかった。→
だから
あなたの力になりたくて…。
I wanted to help you.
Jin!
ジンさん！
（レイツェル）ジン　大丈夫!?
Jin, are you okay?
あ…　ああ。　何でもない。
Yeah, it's nothing.
心の声
（レイツェル）まだ　パズルは
あなたを苦しめている。→
Puzzles are still torturing you.
あのころと同じように…。
Just like back then.
回想
ジン？
Jin?
俺が入る前に
誰かが　この愚者のパズルで…。
Someone got here before me, and...
回想
（ジン）うっ！→
やめろ…　そのパズルは…。
Stop!
Not that puzzle! Not you!
お前は誰だ？　なぜ俺に…　うぅ…。
Why would you...
ジン　どうしたの!?
しっかりして　ジン！
Jin! What's wrong?
Wake up, Jin!
After that, Jin left Raetsel behind and went on to fight Count Pythagoras.
（エニグマ）
その後　ジンは　レイツェルを置いて→
ピタゴラス伯爵との戦いに向かった。
そして　記憶を失い
捕らわれの身となった。
There, he lost his memories and was imprisoned.
だが　ジンは
私に　ある使命を託していた。
However, he gave me a mission.
使命？
A mission?
If something happened to him, I was to gather those following his ideals and fulfill his goal.
（エニグマ）ジンの身に
万が一の事があった場合→
彼の意志を　受け継ぐ者たちを集め
その目的を　成し遂げる事。
His goal? Annihilating all puzzlers, then?
ジンの意志…。　それが
全てのパズラーを滅ぼす事だと？
Jin wanted to solve the Divine Puzzle, get the Divine Scripture,
ジンは　神のパズルを解き
神の書を　手に入れ→
その手で　世界中のパズラーを
滅ぼすつもりだったんだよ。
and destroy every puzzler on the globe.
そのような記録は　ありません。
There is no evidence of that.
I heard about Raetsel from Jin as well.
レイツェルの事も
ジンから聞いていてね。
行方を突き止め
私の計画を話した。
I found her and told her about my plan.
Of course, she decided to help.
無論　賛同してくれたよ。
ジンに
「何かが欠けている」と言われ→
Even though Jin told her she lacks something and left her behind,
置いていかれたにも
かかわらずね。→
Raetsel's devotion to Jin is nothing short of impressive.
レイツェルの　ジンへの忠誠心には
心から敬意を表するよ。
President, I'd like to hear about you as well, not only Raetsel.
大統領。　レイツェルではなく
あなたの事も→
お聞きしたいのですが。
何かな？
What exactly?
ジンとは
一体　どこで出会ったのですか？
Where did you meet Jin?
彼が　まだ　ＰＯＧにいたころ→
When he was still in the ranks of the POG.
私は　日本に
滞在していた事があってね。
I spent some time in Japan.
（バロン）
あなたのような友人がいると→
Jin never mentioned becoming friends with you.
ジンから聞いた事は
ありませんでしたが…。
I heard a lot about you though, Kaidou Baron.
（エニグマ）君の事は　よく聞いていたよ
解道バロン君。→
君のパズルでは　物足りなくなり→
Your puzzles could no longer satisfy Jin,
so he took to challenging Sage Puzzles.
彼は　賢者のパズルに
挑むようになったそうだね。
そんな事まで…。
You know that?
But why would he trust you with the Master Brains?
では　ジンさんは　なぜ　あなたに
マスターブレインの事を託したのですか？
パズルとは　全く関わりのない
あなたに。
You had nothing to do with puzzles.
あなたも　パズルに
何か恨みがあるのですか？
Do you have something against puzzles too?
フッ。　パズルは　人を傷つけ
命を奪うもの。
Puzzles hurt and murder people.
恨む事に
特別な理由が必要かな？→
Do I need some special reason to despise them?
他に　何か質問は？
Do you have any other questions?
（ルーク）最後に　もう一つだけ…。
レイツェル。
何よ？
Just one more.
Raetsel.
What?
確かに　ジンの中にも
パズルへの疑念はあった。→
Jin did question puzzles.
苦しんでいたのかもしれない。
He might have been suffering.
けど　一緒にいる間　パズルの楽しさも
君に教えようとしたはずだよ。→
But I'm sure that during your time together, he tried to show you how fun puzzles are.
That's what the Jin I know would do.
僕の知っているジンは
そういう人だ。
He did that too.
そんな事もあったわね…。
But I'll hate the puzzles that hurt Jin and took him from me.
でも　私は　ジンを苦しめたパズルを
奪ったパズルを憎む！→
そして　全てのパズラーを葬り去った
そのあとは…。
And once we've made all puzzlers a thing of the past...
そのあとは？
Then?
私も　パズルを捨てる。
I'll abandon puzzles too.
ジンが…
ジンが　そうしろと言ったから！
Jin... Jin told me to do that!
He did?
ジンが!?
（ジン）あ…。
回想
レイツェル…。　君は
パズルを捨ててもいいんだよ。
Raetsel, you can abandon puzzles if you want.
パズルを捨てろって!?
He told you to abandon puzzles?!
本当に　ジンが　そんな事を？
ルーク様…。
Did Jin really say that?
Sir Rook...
（ジン）言った…。
I did.
確かに…　僕は　君に
「パズルを捨てていい」って…。
I did tell you that you can abandon puzzles if you want.
It was night... I remember the sound of the waves.
夜だった。　波の音？
浜辺…　浜辺で…。
It was on a beach.
ジン！
Jin!
また　思い出してくれた！
You remembered!
I knew only I could help you get back your memories!
やっぱり　やっぱり　ジンの記憶を
取り戻せるのは　私だけなのよ。→
You need me, Jin!
ジンには…
ジンには　私が必要なのよ！→
Jin!
ジン！　フフッ　アハハハ。
（アナ・グラム）
ふ～ん。　そんな事があったんだ。
That really happened?
（キュービック・Ｇ）
でも　ジンさんが　エニグマに
パズラーを滅ぼしてくれって→
I still can't believe that Jin asked Enigma to annihilate all puzzlers.
頼んだなんて
やっぱり信じられないよ。
He said he'd tell us everything...
何でも答えるって言ってたけど…。
（ルーク）エニグマは何かを隠してるね。
I'm sure he's still hiding something.
（ビショップ）それに　彼の話を裏付ける
証拠もありません。
Not to mention, there's nothing to support his side of the story.
やっぱり
ジンジンが思い出すしかないんだな。
Jinjin will have to remember then.
手は尽くしたよ。　それでも
記憶が戻らないという事は…。
We tried what we could.
If his memories still won't return...
という事は？
What then?
That might mean conventional methods are useless.
普通のやり方では
駄目なのかもしれませんね。
（キュービック）えっ　どうして？
What do you mean?
Just think about it. Why did Jin lose his memories in the first place?
思い出してごらん。　そもそも
なぜ　ジンが記憶を失ったのか…。
神のパズル！
The Divine Puzzle!
It gets unlocked by the battle of two Phi Brains
２人の　ファイ・ブレインが対決する事で
解放され→
and awards the Divine Scripture containing all the knowledge of the world.
この世の全ての理を記した
神の書を→
手に入れる事ができる　神のパズル。
The Divine Puzzle...
（ルーク）かつて　ジンは
神のパズルで　ピタゴラス伯爵と対決し→
Jin fought Count Pythagoras in the Divine Puzzle.
その代償として　伯爵は命を縮め
ジンは記憶を失った。
As the price, the Count paid with his life,
and Jin lost his memories.
（ビショップ）
その時　手に入れた　神の書も…。
We lost the Divine Scripture too.
神のパズルと　神の書。
The Divine Puzzle and the Divine Scripture...
There might be some clues in there about how to return Jin's memories.
そこに　ジンの記憶を取り戻す
手がかりが隠されているのかも…。
神のパズル…　神の書…。
The Divine Puzzle... The Divine Scripture...
I didn't expect it to come up again at this point.
まさか　ここにきて　また
あんなものが出てくるなんて。
きっと　まだ終わってないの。
I'm sure it isn't over yet.
アナたちは
まだ　神のパズルの中にいる…。
We're still in the Divine Puzzle.
（レイツェル）なぜ　急に　あんな事を？
Why would you do that?
Sorry. Jin wouldn't remember anything...
すまない。
なかなか　ジンが　昔の事を→
思い出してくれないのでね
つい…。
大門カイトを倒し　ジンの記憶を
取り戻すのは　この私。
I will be the one to beat Daimon Kaito and return Jin's memories.
それが契約よ。
That's our agreement.
本当に　すまなかった　レイツェル。
私も　つらいのだよ。
I'm really sorry.
Raetsel, it's hard for me too,
敬愛する真方ジンに
何もできずにいる自分が…。
being unable to do anything for the Jin I so revere.
Thing is, if you pull something like this again,
とにかく　これ以上
勝手な事をするなら→
私にも考えがあるから。
I have my own ideas.
You remembered.
（レイツェル）思い出してくれた…
また　思い出してくれた！
やった～！　アハハッ　フフフ　アハハハ…。
Hurray!
敬愛？　敬愛…。
Revere? Revere?
敬愛する…　真方ジン？
The Jin I so revere?
ア…　アハハ…。
フッ。　今日は　ここまで。→
This should be it for today.
I should savor every moment of this puzzle.
せっかくのパズルだ。→
もっと　じっくり　ゆっくり
楽しまないとね。
It's a simple but strong, and most of all, warm puzzle.
回想
（大門カイト）シンプルだけど　強くて
そして　あったかいパズルだった。→
これが　あんたのパズルなんだよ。
This is your puzzle.
Enjoy this Fools' Puzzle that Makata Jin built.
回想
（エニグマ）真方ジンが作った
この愚者のパズルで…。
（バロン）ジン。
Jin.
どうしたんだ？
What's wrong?
エニグマという男の話を聞いても
何も思い出せなかった。
I couldn't remember anything even after listening to Enigma.
焦る事はないさ。
Don't worry about it.
でも　僕は
カイト君と約束したんだ。
But I promised Kaito that I'd find the me that taught him about puzzles.
彼にパズルを教えた
真方ジンを取り戻す。
それが
これからの闘いだって。
That's my battle for now.
You have remembered some things, right?
思い出した事も　あるんだろ？
邪魔な　おやじ。
Such an annoying old fart.
（ジン）思い出した事？
（バロン）ああ。→
Remembered?
Did you really tell Raetsel that she can abandon puzzles if she wants?
「パズルを捨ててもいい」。　本当に
レイツェル君に　そう言ったのか？
それは本当だと思う。
それが　どうかしたのかい？
I think that's true.
Why are you asking?
いや…　少し　おかしいと思ってね。
I just found it a bit confusing.
You once told the young Kaito
かつて　お前は
幼いカイト君に　こう言った。→
when he'd lost his parents, lost all hope,
両親を失い　希望を失い→
and was about to throw puzzles, the last support of his heart, away too,
心の支えである　パズルまで
捨てようとした　カイト君に…。
回想
（ジン）大切なものは
手放すな。　絶対に…。
"Don't let go of what's important.
"No matter what."
Yet you told Raetsel that she can abandon puzzles if she wants.
（バロン）なのに　レイツェル君には
「パズルを捨ててもいい」と言った。
But why?
どういう事なんだろう？
分からない…。
カイト君の事も覚えていない。
I don't know. I don't remember that episode with Kaito either.
But...
でも…。
（バロン）でも？
But?
But she lacks something. That's what I feel.
（ジン）
彼女には　何かが欠けている。
そんな気がする。
その事と関係があるのかも。
It might be related to that.
何か…。　何かって？
Something? But what?
（ジン）それも分からない。
I don't know that either.
恐らく　パズルに関する事だと思う。
But I guess it has something to do with puzzles.
つまり　レイツェル君にはなくて
カイト君にはあるもの…。
Something that Kaito has but Raetsel lacks.
I think I needed Kaito because he had it.
恐らく　当時の僕は→
その「何か」を持っている　カイト君を
必要としたような気がする。
（バロン）だから　カイト君には
「パズルを捨てるな」と。→
That's why you told Kaito not to throw puzzles away?
そして　レイツェル君には…。
And to Raetsel you said...
I loved puzzles. I hated puzzles.
（ジン）パズルを愛し　パズルを憎み→
I guided Kaito. I abandoned Raetsel.
カイト君を導き　レイツェルを捨てた。
真方ジン…
お前は　一体　何者なんだ？
Makata Jin... Just who were you?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
It's a lie! It can't be!
うそだ！　うそだ！
ジンが　私より　カイトを必要？
Jin can't need Kaito more than me!
私…　私より…。　うそだ！
Not more than me! No!
う…　うそだ。　うそ…。
It can't be! It can't!
うそだ～！
It can't be!
No. That's not it.
（レイツェル）違う…　違う…。
No.
違う！　ジンは　私のもの。
Jin's mine.
絶対に　誰にも…
誰にも渡さない！
I won't let anyone have him.
レイツェル!?
Raetsel?
一緒に行きましょう　ジン。
Let's go together, Jin.
一緒に…　今から？　どこへだい？
Together?
Now?
Where?
（レイツェル）私とジンしか知らない
あの場所へ。→
To that place only you and I know.
私と　あそこへ行けば→
If we go there, all your memories will return.
あなたの記憶は
全て　よみがえるわ。→
さあ　行きましょ　ジン。
Come now, Jin.
Jin disappeared?
ジンさんが姿を消した!?
I called the POG to look for him.
ＰＯＧに連絡し
捜索を始めてもらっています。
What do we do now? We promised Kaito!
どうしよう!?
カイトと約束したのに！
さ…　捜さなきゃ。
イワシミズ君！　虫メカ発進　用意！
We've gotta find him!
Iwashimizu! Launch the bugs!
Roger.
（イワシミズ君）ガッテン！　カタパルト　準備よし。
Ready to launch.
Calm down, Cubik.
落ち着いて　キュービック君。
でも～。
But!
（アナ）みんな～！　この子がね→
Guys! She says she saw Jinjin leave!
ジンジンが出てくのを見てたって。
（鳴き声）
（ソウジ　キュービック）え～!?
（バロン）１人で　ですか？
Alone?
ん～？　それが～…。
Well, as for that...
捜せ。　諜報部の総力を挙げて
真方ジンを捜すのだ。
Find him.
This is intelligence's top priority now.
Find Makata Jin.
レイツェル…。
（レイツェル）ミャーオ。→
Raetsel...
言ったでしょ
私にも考えがあるって。
I told you I have my ideas.
これは契約違反ではないのかね？
Is this not a violation of our contract?
そうだったかしら？
それで　ジンは　どこにいる？
Is it?
Where is Jin?
ウフッ　知りたい？　大統領。
Wanna know, Mr. President?
野良猫が…。
Damn stray cat.
フン。
（井藤ノノハ）
え～！　どういう事なのよ!?
What? What's going on?
分かんねえよ！
とにかく　レイツェルが→
How should I know?
Point is that Raetsel took Jin and vanished!
ジンをつれて
どっか行きやがった！
（逆之上ギャモン）
ったく…　あんの黒猫娘！
Damn that black cat.
Freecell and Pinochle are arranging a flight—
今　フリーセルとピノクルが
飛行機の手配をしてくれて…。
[無線]
NUMBER HIDDEN
誰だ？
Who is it?
[無線]ウフフッ　私。　分かる？
Me. Got it?
あ…　レイツェル！
な…。
えっ!?
Raetsel!
What are you gonna do to Jin?
お前　ジンを　どうするつもりだ!?
（レイツェル）失礼ねぇ。　これは　パズルよ。
Oh, come on. This is a puzzle.
ギヴァーは私。　ソルヴァーは君。→
I'm the Giver.
You're the Solver.
The treasure is Makata Jin.
そして　財は…　真方ジン。
Try solving the puzzle! Try finding us!
[無線]さあ　このパズルを解いて
私たちを見つけてごらんなさい。
Preview
I'm a basketball prodigy! Stop making me do the fundamentals!
Dribble to the baselines 500 times! If you fail, you have to start again from zero!